Guide to the Robert Moses Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert Moses papers
1934-1970
MS 360
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.42
(15 boxes)
Mimeographed and printed matter, together with a few photocopies of letters, compiled by Robert Moses. These form a record of projects which he sponsored or was connected with, particularly the New York World's Fair (1964-1965), the Power Authority of the state of New York and the Triborough Bridge Authority. Also clippings of newspaper and magazine articles by and about him, texts of speeches and reports by agencies of which he was a member.
Moses, Robert, 1888-1981
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert Moses, 1966-1970; and Mrs. Robert Moses, 1981; part transferred from the Harold Phelps Stokes Papers.
Scope and Contents
The Robert Moses Papers consist of only mimeographed and printed material, and a few photocopies of letters. (Most of Robert Moses' papers are at the New York Public Library.) The bulk of this material was arranged and bound in 38 volumes by Moses; he also prepared a table of contents to each volume. Annotated photocopies of these tables of contents will be found in the appendix to this register; they provide a detailed, item-by-item listing of most of the collection. However, there are also some materials not bound in volumes. These are arranged chronologically and boxed at the end of the collection, and there is no detailed listing of them.
Some of the papers were given to Yale by Robert Moses. Others were removed from the Harold Phelps Stokes Papers, Ms No. 645; that collection still contains the many letters of Moses to Stokes. Finally, two mimeographed speeches were donated by Frank Monaghan. Parts of the collection were formerly catalogued as books, under the call no. Yz.909.M.
Note: Item numbers in Inventory correspond to item placement within bound volumes.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Moses (1888-1981): public official; Parks Commissioner of New York City, 1934-1960; Pres., N.Y. World's Fair 1964-1965; special adviser to N.Y. Governor on housing, 1974-1975; named New Yorker of Year, N.Y. Daily News, 1956; numerous subsequent awards, medals and honors for accomplishment in public service.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Bridges -- New York (State) -- New York; New York (N.Y.) -- Exhibitions; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government; Public officers; Moses, Robert, 1888-1981; Power Authority of the State of New York; Triborough Bridge Authority; New York World's Fair ( 1964-1965 New York, N.Y.)
- Inventory, 1934-(1952-1970)
  - 1952
    - BOOKS
      - AQUARIUM - ITEM # 7 (Box 1)
      - ARBORETUM - ITEM # 8 (Box 1)
      - ATLANTIC BEACH BRIDGE - ITEM # 9 (Box 1)
      - BATTERY PARK - ITEM # 10 (Box 1)
      - BEDFORD AVENUE FIRE - ITEM # 11 (Box 1)
      - BROOKLYN CIVIC CENTER - ITEM # 12 (Box 1)
      - BULOVA WATCH CO. BUILDING - ITEM # 13 (Box 1)
      - CANTON, OHIO - ITEM # 14 (Box 1)
      - COLUMBUS CIRCLE, TITLE I - ITEM # 27 (Box 1)
      - FORDHAM IMPROVEMENT - ITEM # 15 (Box 1)
      - FORT GREENE, TITLE I - ITEM # 28 (Box 1)
      - HIGHBRIDGE INTERCHANGE - ITEM # 16 (Box 1)
      - HOUSING AUTHORITY, 18th ANNUAL REPORT - ITEM # 26 (Box 1)
      - JONES BEACH STADIUM - ITEM # 17 (Box 1)
      - JONES BEACH PARKWAY SYSTEM - ITEM # 18 (Box 1)
      - LINCOLN TUNNEL THIRD TUBE - ITEM # 25 (Box 1)
      - NIAGARA - ITEM # 19 (Box 1)
      - NORTHERN STATE--SAGTIKOS PARKWAYS - ITEM # 20 (Box 1)
      - PARK PROGRESS, 18 YEARS - ITEM # 4 (Box 1)
      - PLANNING COMMISSION - ITEM # 21 (Box 1)
      - PROSPECT PARK MERRY GO ROUND - ITEM # 1 (Box 1)
      - RECREATIONAL FACILITIES - ITEM # 2 (Box 1)
      - ROCKAWAYS DINNER - ITEM # 3 (Box 1)
      - SEAGIRT BOULEVARD - ITEM # 22 (Box 1)
      - STATEN ISLAND RAPID TRANSIT - ITEM # 23 (Box 1)
      - TIDELANDS LETTER - ITEM # 5 (Box 1)
      - TIDELANDS STATEMENT - ITEM # 6 (Box 1)
      - VANDALISM - ITEM # 24 (Box 1)
    - MAGAZINE & NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
      - 1. JOURNAL AMERICAN--IS STRANGULATION NECESSARY? (Box 1)
      - 2. LIFE--FROM A MOST INDEPENDENT INDEPENDENT REPUBLICAN (Box 1)
      - 3. METROPOLITAN GOLFER--BOB MOSES--PUBLINKERS PAL (Box 1)
      - 4. MUNICIPAL ENGINEERS--BUILDING NEW YORK CITY (Box 1)
      - 5. NEW YORKER--MOSES REVISITED (Box 1)
      - 6. ORDNANCE ENGINEERS--DUAL PURPOSE CONSTRUCTION (Box 1)
      - 7. POLICE MAGAZINE--N. Y. C. RECREATIONAL FACILITIES (Box 1)
      - 8. ROCKAWAY REVIEW--JAMAICA BAY (Box 1)
      - 9. ROCKAWAY REVIEW--ROCKAWAY (Box 1)
      - 10. ROCKAWAY REVIEW--ROCKAWAY PARKS (Box 1)
      - 11. STATEN ISLAND ADVANCE--MR. BETTER CITY-COORDINATOR MOSES (Box 1)
      - 12. TIMES, NEW YORK--BOAT BASINS (Box 1)
      - 13. TIMES, NEW YORK--HINTS ON HOW TO BE ROBERT MOSES (Box 1)
      - 14. U. S. NEWS--BIG CITIES' BIG FUTURE (Box 1)
    - SPEECHES, RELEASES, ETC.
      - 1. AMERICAN INSTITUTE OF ARCHITECTS (Box 1)
      - 2. HARLEM REDEVELOPMENT STORY (Box 1)
      - 3. JENNIE JEROME HOUSE (Box 1)
      - 4. NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY (Box 1)
      - 5. NEW YORK UNIVERSITY-BELLEVUE MEDICAL CENTER (Box 1)
      - 6. RICHMONDTOWN (Box 1)
      - 7. SPEED LIMIT (Box 1)
      - 8. TRIBOROUGH STADIUM (Box 1)
  - 1953
    - BOOKS
      - AIRLINES TERMINAL (Box 1)
      - ARTERIAL REPORT (Box 1)
      - ASSESSED VALUATIONS (Box 1)
      - BARUCH HOUSES AND PLAYGROUND (Box 1)
      - FIRST AVENUE--UNITED NATIONS (Box 1)
      - FLINT, MICHIGAN--CITY HALL (Box 1)
      - GENERAL MOTORS--BETTER HIGHWAYS--WINNING ESSAY (Box 1)
      - GENERAL MOTORS--TOP ESSAYS (Box 1)
      - HOUSING AUTHORITY--19th ANNUAL REPORT (Box 1)
      - KISSENA CORRIDOR--PLAYGROUND (Box 1)
      - NEW YORK UNIVERSITY-BELLEVUE--TITLE I (Box 1)
      - OSBORN MEMORIAL PLAYGROUND (Box 1)
      - PALISADES INTERSTATE PARKWAY OPENING (Box 1)
      - PRATT INSTITUTE AREA--TITLE I (Box 1)
      - RECREATIONAL FACILITIES (Box 1)
      - SOUTH BEACH OCEANFRONT IMPROVEMENT (Box 1)
      - TITLE I PROGRESS REPORT (Box 1)
      - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY ANNUAL REPORT 1953 (Box 1)
      - WASHINGTON SQUARE--TITLE I (Box 1)
    - MAGAZINE & NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
      - DAILY NEWS--SERIES OF ARTICLES FROM OCT. 13-18 INCLUSIVE (Box 1)
      - DAILY NEWS--THE MAKING OF A METROPOLIS (Box 1)
      - FLATBUSH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE--RECREATION AND PEACE (Box 1)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE--JAMAICA BAY FILL PLANTED TO GRASS (Box 1)
      - JOURNAL AMERICAN--MOSES PREDICTS EVEN GREATER ERA (Box 1)
      - LONG ISLAND ASSOCIATION BULLETIN--SYNOPSIS OF SPEECH BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 1)
      - LONG ISLAND FORUM--HISTORY OF JONES BEACH STATE PARK (Box 1)
      - NEW YORK LIFE--SHOULD YOUR CHILD BE A PUBLIC SERVANT? (Box 1)
      - NEW YORK STATE UNIVERSITY--BULLETIN TO SCHOOLS--JAMAICA BAY (Box 1)
      - ORGANIC GARDENING MAGAZINE--RIKER'S ISLAND NURSERY (Box 1)
      - ROCKAWAY REVIEW--A TOUR ALONG THE ROCKAWAY SHORES (Box 1)
      - SATURDAY REVIEW--SHORT STORIES AS I LIKE THEM (Box 1)
      - SEVENTY FIVE MAGAZINE--THE CRY FOR VISION (Box 1)
      - STATEN ISLAND ADVANCE--BROAD VISION IN STATEN ISLAND'S FUTURE (Box 1)
      - TIMES, NEW YORK--ACHIEVEMENTS OF ROBERT MOSES (Box 1)
      - TIMES, NEW YORK--CARROUSELS! SPRING! (Box 1)
      - TIMES, NEW YORK--CITY PARKS RIPPED BY MARCH RAINFALL (Box 1)
      - TIMES, NEW YORK--PROBLEMS--MANY AND A PROGRAM (Box 1)
      - TIMES, NEW YORK--RIKER'S ISLAND--RUSTIC PARADISE (Box 1)
      - TIMES, NEW YORK--TO TURN BACK THE KILLER, SPEED (Box 1)
      - TOWN AND COUNTRY--HIGHWAYS AND MEANS (Box 1)
    - SPEECHES, RELEASES, ETC.
      - BARUCH HOUSES DEDICATION (Box 1)
      - CORLEARS HOOK COOPERATIVE PROJECT (Box 1)
      - CHURCH OF THE OPEN DOOR (Box 1)
      - DETROIT ECONOMIC CLUB (Box 1)
      - DE VEAUX SCHOOL, NIAGARA FALLS (Box 1)
      - EAST SIDE AIRLINES TERMINAL (Box 1)
      - NEW YORK BOTANICAL GARDEN (Box 1)
      - RICHMONDTOWN--PRESS RELEASE (Box 1)
      - SYNTHETIC TOPSOIL--PROGRESS STATEMENTS (Box 1)
      - TIDELANDS TESTIMONY BEFORE SENATE (Box 1)
      - UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN (Box 1)
      - VIVIEN KELLEMS (Box 1)
  - 1956: 1st volume
    - BOOKS
      - FUTURE SUBURBAN PARKS BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 1)
      - HAMMELS--ROCKAWAY TITLE ONE SLUM CLEARANCE (Box 1)
      - HOFFMAN AND SWINBURNE ISLANDS PROTECTION AND EXTENSION OF SOUTH BEACH PARK IN THE LOWER BAY AT STATEN ISLAND (Box 1)
      - JOINTLY OPERATED PLAYGROUNDS (Box 1)
      - LINCOLN SQUARE--TITLE ONE SLUM CLEARANCE (Box 1)
      - MEADOWBROOK STATE PARKWAY EXTENSION (Box 1)
      - NEW YORK COLISEUM--COLUMBUS CIRCLE (Box 1)
      - PARK ROW--TITLE ONE SLUM CLEARANCE (Box 1)
      - PRINCIPLES GOVERNING THE ESTABLISHMENT, EXTENSION AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE PARK AND PARKWAY SYSTEM OF NEW YORK STATE (Box 1)
      - PROGRESS--1954-1955--REPORT TO MAYOR BY CITY CONSTRUCTION COORDINATOR (Box 1)
      - PROPOSED COOPERATIVE HOUSING PROGRAM FOR BUILDING AND CONSTRUCTION TRADES COUNCIL OF NEW YORK CITY (Box 1)
      - RAILROAD GRADE CROSSING ELIMINATION PROGRESS NEW YORK CITY (Box 1)
      - RECREATIONAL FACILITIES FOR NEW YORKERS (Box 1)
      - RICHMONDTOWN RESTORATION (Box 1)
      - ST. JOHN'S RECREATION CENTER (Box 1)
      - SEWARD PARK--TITLE ONE SLUM CLEARANCE (Box 1)
      - TITLE ONE SLUM CLEARANCE PROGRESS (Box 1)
      - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY REPORT (Box 1)
      - TWENTY-TWO YEARS PARK PROGRESS (Box 1)
      - VAN VOORHEES PARK (Box 1)
      - WORKABLE PROGRAM RE: SLUMS (Box 1)
    - MAGAZINE AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
      - DAILY MIRROR--MOSES, THE BUILDER (Box 1)
      - DAILY NEWS--ROBERT MOSES, THE NEW YORKER OF THE YEAR (Box 1)
      - FORD MOTOR COMPANY--WE CAN LICK CONGESTION (Box 1)
      - HARPERS MAGAZINE--THE NEW SUPER HIGHWAYS--BLESSING OR BLIGHT BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 1)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE--MOSES SAYS CITY CAN LEARN FROM PARK SYSTEM IN SPAIN (Box 1)
      - JOURNAL AMERICAN--YOUR NEW YORK OF TOMORROW (Box 1)
      - LONG ISLAND PRESS--LET'S DO SOMETHING ABOUT OUR SALT-WATER COWBOYS BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 1)
      - NEW YORK POST--ROBERT MOSES BY IRWIN ROSS (Box 1)
      - ROCKAWAY REVIEW--ROCKAWAY IMPROVEMENT PLAN (Box 1)
      - SATURDAY EVENING POST--WHY I AM A CONSERVATIVE (Box 1)
      - STATEN ISLAND ADVANCE--MOSES LOOKS AT FUTURE--"IT'LL BE STUPENDOUS" (Box 1)
      - TIMES--"SIGNIFICANCE: WHAT THE CITY MEANS" N. Y. COLISEUM CITY (Box 1)
      - TIMES--STRIKING A BALANCE ON ROBERT MOSES (Box 1)
      - TIMES--THE MOSES RECIPE FOR BETTER PARKS (Box 1)
      - WORLD TELEGRAM--ROBERT MOSES REPORTS ON CARE ACCORDED STATUES (Box 1)
  - 1956: 2nd volume
    - SPEECHES, RELEASES, ETC.
      - AMATEUR ATHLETIC UNION--INTRODUCTION OF JAMES FARLEY BY ROBERT MOSES AT WALDORF (Box 1)
      - BROOKLYN POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE--"CONTOURS OF SCIENCE" (Box 1)
      - BROWNSVILLE BOYS' CLUB DINNER--WALDORF ASTORIA (Box 1)
      - CARNEGIE HALL--RM's SPEECH AT UNITED HOUSING FOUNDATION MEETING (Box 1)
      - CITY HALL REDEDICATION (Box 1)
      - CITY HALL--REMARKS OF ROBERT MOSES AT SWEARING IN OF JUDGE IRVING BEN COOPER (Box 1)
      - CLEARVIEW EXPRESSWAY IMPROVEMENT--OPENING OF INFORMATION AND RELOCATION OFFICE (Box 1)
      - COMMENTS BY ROBERT MOSES ON WRCA TV AND RADIO BROADCASTS RE: CONCESSIONS (Box 1)
      - COMMODORE HOTEL--TALK BY RM AT 70th ANNIVERSARY UNIVERSITY SETTLEMENT IN AMERICA (Box 1)
      - DUFFY SQUARE--CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN ROBERT MOSES AND T. J. McINERNEY OF BROADWAY ASSOCIATION AND W. J. SALMON OF ATLANTIC LEASING CO. (Box 1)
      - FUGITIVE THOUGHTS ABOUT PLANNING AND MODERN ARCHITECTURE (TEXAS SOCIETY OF ARCHITECTS, DRISKILL HOTEL, CORPUS CHRISTI--RECORDED SPEECH BY ROBERT MOSES) (Box 1)
      - HANS CHRISTIAN ANDERSEN DEDICATION (Box 1)
      - HEARING ON HORACE HARDING EXPRESSWAY EXTENSION (Box 1)
      - INTERNATIONAL ST. LAWRENCE--RM's TALK AT CHATEAU LAURIER, OTTAWA (Box 1)
      - LEGISLATIVE CORRESPONDENTS' DINNER--SHERATON TEN EYCK HOTEL (Box 1)
      - LINCOLN SQUARE--N. Y. BUILDING CONGRESS LUNCHEON--SHERATON ASTOR (Box 1)
      - NEW YORK BOTANICAL GARDEN--REMARKS BY RM AT DEDICATION OF NEW LABORATORY BUILDING (Box 1)
      - PARK INN--TALK BY RM AT ROCKAWAY BRANCH OPENING CELEBRATION (Box 1)
      - PARK SHERATON HOTEL--REMARKS OF RM AT ANNUAL MEETING OF HOTEL ASSOCIATION OF NEW YORK CITY (Box 1)
      - PLANNING--SOME SLIPS BETWEEN THE CUP OF VISION AND THE LIP OF REALIZATION--PRINCETON UNIVERSITY (Box 1)
      - POWER AUTHORITY OF STATE OF NEW YORK--RM's TALK AT NEW YORK STATE SOCIETY OF NEWSPAPER EDITORS' DINNER (Box 1)
      - PROPOSITION NUMBER ONE--RM REVIEWS HIGHWAY CONSTRUCTION PROGRESS (Box 1)
      - SHERATON ASTOR--INTRODUCTION OF GEORGE MEANY AT LUNCHEON OF NEW YORK BUILDING CONGRESS SHERATON BROCK HOTEL--RM's REMARKS ON NIAGARA FRONTIER (Box 1)
      - SHERATON BROCK HOTEL - RM'S REMARKS ON NIAGARA FRONTIER (Box 1)
      - STATEMENT BY RM--1957 CAPITAL BUDGET (Box 1)
      - STATEMENT BY RM--FOR JOURNAL AMERICAN (Box 1)
      - STATEMENT BY RM--CONCERNING LOCAL LAWS AFFECTING PARK OPERATIONS AND CONCESSIONS INTRODUCED BY COUNCILMAN ISAACS (Box 1)
      - STATEMENT BY RM--HEARING BEFORE JOINT LEGISLATIVE COMMITTEE ON MOTOR BOATS (Box 1)
      - STATEMENT BY RM--ANSWER TO REQUEST FOR AN OPINION ON THE NEW YORK STATE--NEW YORK CITY FISCAL RELATIONS (Box 1)
      - STATEMENT BY RM--NEW YORK STATE TEMPORARY HIGHWAY FINANCE COMMISSION (Box 1)
      - TALK BY RM--LUNCHEON OF ST. LAWRENCE VALLEY ASSOCIATION--CHAMBER OF COMMERCE OF MASSENA, N. Y. (Box 1)
      - TAVERN-ON-THE-GREEN (Box 1)
      - RM's LETTER TO ARNOLD NEWMAN AND STATEMENT RELATING TO CHANGES IN CITY PLANNING (Box 1)
      - RM's LETTER TO HON. JOSEPH T. SHARKEY, MAJORITY LEADER--CITY COUNCIL (Box 1)
      - ANSWERS TO QUESTIONS DIRECTED TO ROBERT MOSES AND STUART CONSTABLE BY PRESS VAN VOORHEES PARK CEREMONIES (Box 1)
      - WALDORF ASTORIA--REMARKS BY RM AT ANNUAL DINNER OF BUILDING TRADES EMPLOYERS ASSOCIATION OF N. Y. C. (Box 1)
      - WALDORF ASTORIA--TALK BY ROBERT MOSES--FIFTH AVENUE ASSOCIATION (Box 1)
      - WEEPING BEECH PARK AND PLAYGROUND--ROBERT MOSES' DEDICATION SPEECH (Box 1)
      - WILDLIFE REFUGE IN JAMAICA BAY ISLANDS--CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN ROBERT MOSES AND GEOFFREY CARLETON, LINNAEAN SOCIETY OF NEW YORK (Box 1)
  - 1956: 3rd volume
    - POWER AUTHORITY OF STATE OF NEW YORK
      - MEMORANDUM DATED JAN. 12, 1956 RE: FEDERAL LEGISLATION TO PRESERVE AND ENHANCE THE SCENIC BEAUTY OF THE NIAGARA AND TO DEVELOP POWER (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - APPLICATION OF POWER AUTHORITY FOR LICENSE TO DEVELOP THE NIAGARA RIVER DATED AUGUST 20, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - AMENDMENT TO SUCH APPLICATION DATED SEPTEMBER 19, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - MEMORANDUM IN SUPPORT OF SUCH APPLICATION DATED NOVEMBER 14, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - PETITION FOR REHEARING OF POWER AUTHORITY APPLICATION DATED DECEMBER 4, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - MEMORANDUM IN SUPPORT OF SUCH PETITION DATED DECEMBER 4, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - POWER AUTHORITY--25th ANNUAL REPORT (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE POWER PROJECT (Construction Progress) January, February, March, April, May, June, July, August, September, October, November and December (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE CONTRACT S--2--POWER CONTRACT WITH PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION OF VERMONT (January 25, 1956) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE CONTRACT S--3--POWER CONTRACT WITH CITY OF PLATTSBURGH (January 25, 1956) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE CONTRACT S--4--POWER CONTRACT WITH U.S. AIR FORCE (January 25, 1956) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE SEAWAY--POWER FOLDER (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - SEAWAY--POWER FOLDER "HOW TO SEE THE ST. LAWRENCE POWER AND SEAWAY PROJECTS--1956" (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - STATEMENT BY CHAIRMAN ROBERT MOSES DATED NOVEMBER 15, 1956 RE: CONTRACT WITH MUNICIPALITIES (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - STATEMENT TO PUBLIC WORKS COMMITTEE OF HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES ON LEHMAN BILL BY ROBERT MOSES, DATED JUNE 28, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1957: 1st volume
    - POWER AUTHORITY OF THE STATE OF NEW YORK
      - AS A RESULT OF THE DESTRUCTION IN 1956 OF THE SCHOELLKOPF POWER PLANT…THE NIAGARA AREA IS FACED WITH AN EMERGENCY (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - A HOLIDAY MESSAGE TO THE NIAGARA FRONTIER BY ROBERT MOSES--GUEST EDITOR NIAGARA FALLS GAZETTE (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - GROUNDBREAKING CEREMONIES--REYNOLDS ALUMINUM & GENERAL MOTORS PLANTS AT ROOSEVELTOWN ON ST. LAWRENCE RIVER (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - MEMORANDUM TO HON. AUSTIN W. ERWIN, CHAIRMAN FINANCE COMMITTEE, NEW YORK STATE SENATE FROM ROBERT MOSES RE: AN ACT TO AMEND PUBLIC AUTHORITIES LAW IN RELATION TO CONSUMER RATES AND SERVICES (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - MEMORANDUM IN OPPOSITION--AN ACT TO AMEND PUBLIC AUTHORITIES LAW IN RELATION TO PAYMENT OF TAXES UPON PROPERTY, FACILITIES AND ACTIVITIES OF NIAGARA RIVER PROJECT (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - MEMORANDUM WITH RESPECT TO STAFF REPORT ON PUBLIC AUTHORITIES OF TEMPORARY STATE COMMISSION ON COORDINATION OF STATE ACTIVITIES (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - NIAGARA POWER--LETTER TO HON. JOSEPH S. CLARK 3/12/57 RE: ECONOMIC TRANSMISSION (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - NIAGARA POWER AND LOCAL TAXES (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - NIAGARA POWER PROJECT, CONDUITS, RESERVOIR (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - POWER MARKETING (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - PRELIMINARY REPORT--RECENT PROGRESS IN NUCLEAR POWER AND ITS EFFECT ON NIAGARA FALLS POWER PROJECT (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - REPORT ON VISIT TO EUROPE - AUGUST-SEPTEMBER 1957--TO REVIEW NUCLEAR POWER DEVELOPMENT BY THOMAS F. FARRELL (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - REPORT ON RECENT PROGRESS ON NUCLEAR POWER AND ITS EFFECT ON NIAGARA FALLS PROJECT BY THOMAS F. FARRELL (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - ROBERT MOSES' LETTER OCTOBER 17th RE: REPORT ON NUCLEAR POWER EFFECTS ON NIAGARA POWER STATEMENT TO SENATE COMMITTEE--PUBLIC WORKS IN NIAGARA POWER LICENSING (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE NIAGARA 26th ANNUAL REPORT (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE POWER PROGRESS CONSTRUCTION REPORTS--JANUARY, FEBRUARY, MARCH, APRIL, MAY, JUNE, JULY, AUGUST, SEPTEMBER, OCTOBER, NOVEMBER, DECEMBER (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - ST. LAWRENCE & NIAGARA POWER BY ROBERT MOSES AT AMERICAN SOCIETY OF CIVIL ENGINEERS (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - STATEMENT OF ROBERT MOSES ON NIAGARA POWER OVER WBEN, BUFFALO AND WNYC (Box 2A, Folder 1)
  - 1957: 2nd volume
    - BOOKS
      - BRONX APPROACHES TO THROGS NECK BRIDGE AND RELOCATION OF HOMES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - CLEARVIEW EXPRESSWAY AND RELOCATION OF HOMES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - DANCE--MUSIC--DRAMA (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - DELANCEY STREET HOUSES--SCHEDULES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - LA GUARDIA MEMORIAL (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - LINCOLN SQUARE--SCHEDULES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - MEMORANDUM OPPOSING BILLS SPONSORED BY TEMPORARY STATE COMMISSION ON COORDINATION OF STATE ACTIVITIES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - MILLER HIGHWAY WEST SIDE ELEVATED IMPROVEMENT (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - NEW YORK AQUARIUM ON OCEANFRONT (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - NARROWS BRIDGE RELOCATION AT STATEN ISLAND (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - PALISADES INTERSTATE PARKWAY--NEW JERSEY SECTION COMPLETION (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - PARK ROW HOUSES--SCHEDULES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - PENN STATION SOUTH--TITLE ONE SLUM CLEARANCE (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - RECREATIONAL FACILITIES FOR NEW YORKERS (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - SEWARD PARK HOUSES SCHEDULE (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - STATEN ISLAND OCEANFRONT IMPROVEMENT (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - SUNKEN MEADOW STATE PARK AND PARKWAY IMPROVEMENT (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - THROGS NECK BRIDGE (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - TITLE ONE SLUM CLEARANCE PROGRESS REPORT (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE & TUNNEL AUTHORITY ANNUAL REPORT (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE & TUNNEL AUTHORITY MAP (Box 2A, Folder 2)
    - MAGAZINES AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
      - FLATBUSH--NEW CREATIONAL FACILITIES IN AND ABOUT FLATBUSH (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - HARPER'S MAGAZINE--CIVIL DEFENSE FIASCO BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - HARVARD CRIMSON--YOUNG MAN--GO EAST BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE--COMMISSIONER MOSES ANSWERS HIS MAIL (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE--"COMEUPPANCE" FOR THE AUTOMOBILE BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE--MOB RULE IS NOT DEMOCRACY BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE--THEATRE IN THE PARKS BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE--VOTE "NO" BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - LONG ISLAND BABYLON POST--A PROGRAM FOR OUTER BEACHES BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - LONG ISLAND SUNDAY PRESS--THE WORLD'S BUSIEST SANDMAN BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - NEWSDAY--CANDIDATE MUST TAKE A STAND (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - READERS DIGEST--HOW TO GET THINGS DONE--IF YOU'RE ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - ROCKAWAY REVIEW--EXPANSION OF ROCKAWAYS' RECREATIONAL FACILITIES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - SPORTS ILLUSTRATED--THE DODGERS MOVE BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - SUNDAY TELEGRAM--WORCESTER, MASS.--LEADERSHIP IN NEW WORCESTER (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - TIMES MAGAZINE--LA GUARDIA--A SALUTE AND A MEMOIR (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - THE WESTSIDER--ALL BRIDGES AND TUNNELS LEAD TO MANHATTAN BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - THE WESTSIDER--HOUSING AND TRAFFIC RELIEF BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2A, Folder 2)
  - 1957: 3rd volume
    - SPEECHES, RELEASES, ETC.
      - ANOTHER NEW YORK STATE CONSTITUTIONAL CONVENTION--BY ROBERT MOSES, ST. JOHN'S LAW REVIEW (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - AQUARIUM OPENING--REMARKS OF ROBERT MOSES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - CASTLE CLINTON DEVELOPMENT IN BATTERY PARK (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - THE CITY--ADVANCE OR DECLINE--SPRINGFIELD ADULT EDUCATION COUNCIL (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - THE COMPLETION OF HORACE HARDING SECTION LONG ISLAND EXPRESSWAY (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - CONFERENCE HOUSE--TOTTENVILLE, S. I.--TALK BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - EYE ON NEW YORK--LINCOLN SQUARE PROJECT (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - HARLEM RIVER DRIVE PLAYGROUNDS OPENING (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - JAMAICA TRACK--INTERVIEW WITH ROBERT MOSES ON WNYC (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - LIGHTHOUSE DEDICATION AND OPEN HOUSE (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - MESSAGE FROM ROBERT MOSES TO GARDEN CLUB OF AMERICA (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - METROPOLITAN PARKS--A MEMORANDUM TO PARTICIPANTS OF ARDEN HOUSE CONFERENCE ON METROPOLITAN PROBLEMS (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - MORNINGSIDE GARDENS CORNERSTONE CEREMONIES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - NEW YORK ZOOLOGICAL SOCIETY ANNUAL MEETING AT WALDORF ASTORIA (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - A NOTE ON PLANNING--SYRACUSE POST-STANDARD (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - OPENING OF NEW JERSEY SECTION OF PALISADES INTERSTATE PARKWAY--JUNE 1957 (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - OPENING OF NORTH HARLEM HOUSES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - PARADE GROUNDS FOR ATHLETIC CENTER (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - RECOMMENDATIONS FOR REGULATION AND CONTROL OF MOTOR BOATING (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - REGIONAL RAIL TRANSPORTATION--A MEMORANDUM TO PARTICIPANTS OF ARDEN HOUSE CONFERENCE ON METROPOLITAN PROBLEMS (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - SALUTE TO LINCOLN SQUARE--WEST SIDE ASSOCIATION LUNCHEON (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - 75th ANNIVERSARY OF STATEN ISLAND INSTITUTE OF ARTS AND SCIENCES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - SHOREFRONT SEWAGE PROBLEMS AND ITS SOLUTION--WNYC (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - SOME PROBLEMS OF URBAN PLANNING BY ROBERT MOSES AT SMITH COLLEGE (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - SOUTH BEACH, STATEN ISLAND--TALK BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - STATEMENT OF ROBERT MOSES ON HEARING ON L. I. EXPRESSWAY, GUINEA WOODS ROAD TO SUFFOLK COUNTY LINE (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - STATEMENT OF ROBERT MOSES FOR HEARING ON OYSTER BAY EXPRESSWAY (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - STATEMENT REGARDING WASHINGTON SQUARE BY ROBERT MOSES (Box 2B, Folder 1)
      - SUMMER THEATRE--WOLLMAN MEMORIAL--ROBERT MOSES' REMARKS (Box 2B, Folder 1)